So next we're going to talk about code generation for if then else
接下来，我们将讨论If Then Else的代码生成
expressions And to do that we're going to need some control flow instructions. So
表达式，要做到这一点，我们需要一些控制流指令。所以
we'll have, we'll need two in fact. So here's the branch equal instruction, and
我们有，实际上我们需要两个。这是分支相等指令，
this jumps to a label if the contents of two registers are equal And then we'll
如果两个寄存器的内容相等，则跳转到标签，然后我们将
also need an unconditional jump. So this just does an unconditional branch, not
还需要一个无条件的跳跃。所以这只是一个无条件的分支，而不是
branch, an unconditional jump to a particular assembly instruction. So let's
分支，即无条件跳转到特定汇编指令。所以让我们
look at the code generation for the expression if E1 is equal to E2 then
查看表达式的代码生成，如果E1等于E2，则
evaluate three otherwise evaluate four. So first we have to evaluate the predicate
评估3，否则评估4。因此，首先我们必须评估谓词
and in order to evaluate the predicate, we first have to evaluate E1. And by now this
为了评估谓词，我们首先必须评估E1。到现在为止，这件事
pattern for binary operation should be familiar. So we evaluate the first
二进制操作的模式应该很熟悉。所以我们评估第一个
sub-expression we save the result on a stack, so we push it on to the stack. It
子表达式我们将结果保存在堆栈上，因此我们将其推送到堆栈上。它
takes two operations, one to save the result of the cumulate on the stack and
执行两个操作，一个是将累加的结果保存到堆栈上，另一个是
the other cumulate stack later. Then we evaluate E2. Now we have evaluate d both
稍后，另一个累加堆栈。然后我们评估E2。现在我们已经评估了d和d
of the arguments to the predicate. The result of E2 is in the accumulator and the
谓词的参数。E2的结果在累加器中，
result of E1 is at the top of the stack because again, the evaluation of E2 will
E1的结果位于堆栈的顶部，因为同样，E2的求值将
preserve the stack. So now we load the value of E One back into a temporary
保留堆栈。所以现在我们将E 1的值重新加载到临时
register. And we pop the stack And then we can actually do the comparison. So now we
注册。然后我们弹出堆栈，然后我们可以实际进行比较。所以现在我们
do a branch equal. So if the value of E One is equal. Sorry this is actually the
做一个相等的树枝。所以如果E 1的值相等。抱歉，这实际上是
value of E Two and E Zero and if that's equal to the value of E One. Then we
E 2和E 0的值，如果它等于E 1的值。那么我们
branch to the true branch. Otherwise we're going to fall through if there not equal.
分支到真正的分支。否则，如果不平等，我们就会失败。
Okay And so we'll call that the false branch And what are we going to do if we
好的，我们称它为假分支，如果我们
fall through, if this test fails, well then we want to evaluate E4. And that will
失败了，如果这个测试失败了，那么我们要评估E4。而那将会
leave the value of E4 in the accumulator and that will be the value of the entire
将E4的值保留在累加器中，这将是整个
if then else in the case where the predicate is false. So when we're done,
If Then Else在谓词为false的情况下。所以当我们做完的时候，
we're going to branch now to some code that we'll just clean up and end the if
我们现在将分支到一些代码，我们将清理这些代码并结束if
statement. We'll see what that does in a moment. Otherwise, we still need to
声明。我们稍后再来看看这会有什么效果。否则，我们还需要
implement the true branch, so we'll stick the label for the true branch here And
实现TRUE分支，因此我们将在这里粘贴TRUE分支的标签
what do we do on the true branch? We just evaluate E3. Okay And then the and if,
我们在真正的分支上做什么？我们只评估E3。好的，然后如果，
Well, actually, there is no cleanup to do Because, E3 and E4 both preserve the
实际上，不需要进行清理，因为E3和E4都保留了
stack, and they leave the result of their expressions of the accumulator. So we
堆栈，它们会留下累加器表达式的结果。所以我们
reach and if, from E3 if we executed the true branch And then, in which case, the
如果从E3执行真分支，则在这种情况下，
value in the accumulator is the value of E3 And we reach and if, through this
累加器中的值是E3的值，并且如果通过这个
branch if we executed the false branch And then the value in the accumulator is the
分支，如果我们执行False分支，则累加器中的值是
value of E4 And so this correctly implements an if then else expression.
值，因此这将正确实现If Then Else表达式。